In May 2025 I retired after 26 years of service in the US Army. For 20 of those years property accountability was my primary focus; I was responsible for the tracking, managing and stewardship of millions of dollars in mission-critical assets. 

After retiring, I took part in GoogleÆs VeteranÆs Launchpad and received training, and later certification, as a Generative AI (Artificial Intelligence) Leader. Subsequently, I was visiting a beloved family member at the time and took the Google AI training in their library, surrounded by their coin collection, 50+ years in the making. When that beloved family member asked me to help them organize their coin collection, my supply sergeant instincts (and newfound enthusiasm for AI), took over and I realized that the same discipline I used to manage military inventory could be powered by AI to help collectors intelligently catalog, research, and manage their treasures. 

While coins are the focus of Numista.AI, the concept will be expanded to include the limitless amount of assets and collectibles out there; baseball cards, paintings, family heirlooms, just about anything that people love to collect and are passionate about.

LinkedIn Bio: www.linkedin.com/in/ericdseaman


